harcourtschool.com 2003-06-21

# Harcourt School Publishers: Customer Privacy Policy

THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES SOLELY TO THE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE WHILE VISITING THE HARCOURT SCHOOL PUBLISHERS ("HARCOURT") WORLD WIDE WEB PAGES ("THE LEARNING SITE"). THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY DO NOT GOVERN PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION FURNISHED THROUGH ANY MEANS OTHER THAN THE LEARNING SITE (SUCH AS BY TELEPHONE OR VIA THE MAIL). 

Harcourt recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of customers and visitors to The Learning Site while permitting Harcourt to conduct legitimate business by providing services and information. 

**By disclosing personally identifiable information to Harcourt, you agree to the terms stated herein.** **Collection and Storage of Information:**

Harcourt will collect certain personal information including, without limitation, your name, mailing address, telephone number and e-mail address when you register for services or purchase products. This information is maintained in Harcourt's customer database. Harcourt may also collect additional information in connection with special offers, contests, or other promotions. 

At the present time, Harcourt does not collect any personally identifiable information from children or from individuals who could be recognized as minors. If Harcourt does so in the future, Harcourt will comply with the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. 

Harcourt may use "cookies" to recognize you and your access privileges on The Learning Site, as well as to trace site usage. A cookie is a piece of information that is sent to your Web browser from a Website and stored on your computer's hard drive. Each time you return to The Learning Site, Harcourt is able to identify you as a previous or registered customer. Cookies also enable us to measure traffic to The Learning Site, including the number of repeat versus new visitors, the time users spend online, and their navigation behavior. Collecting this information allows us to make changes that improve The Learning Site. 

**Use of Information:**

Harcourt uses the information to provide the service or product requested; to enable billing and shipping; to provide you with information about related products and services, based on the preferences you have indicated; to improve The Learning Site; for development of new products and services; and for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. Sometimes Harcourt hires companies to help deliver products or services, like a shipping company that delivers a package. In those instances, Harcourt needs to share your information with them. These companies will be authorized to use the information only to deliver the product or service. In rare instances, Harcourt will disclose personally identifiable information to necessary parties to protect The Learning Site or visitors to The Learning Site, or to enforce compliance with the Terms of Use for The Learning Site. 

Harcourt may share personally identifiable information within the Harcourt family of companies. From time to time, Harcourt may also share its customer lists with other reputable organizations whose products and services are likely to be of interest to its customers. Harcourt will not share your e-mail address with parties outside the Harcourt family of companies. You will be offered the option not to have your personally identifiable information shared with parties outside the Harcourt family of companies. Harcourt will not share personal information, such as mother's maiden name or credit card numbers, with third parties unless Harcourt notifies you otherwise at the time such information is collected. Harcourt will not disclose information concerning individuals' usage of The Learning Site to third parties except in aggregate form. 

Please be aware that if you disclose personally identifiable information on Website message boards or chat areas, that information may be collected and used by third parties without Harcourt's knowledge and may result in unsolicited communications from third parties. Such activities are beyond Harcourt's control. 

**Security of Private Information:**

Harcourt would like to be able to assure you that the information provided is absolutely safe. Unfortunately, several well-publicized instances of computer security breaches make it impossible to be so confident. Harcourt will take reasonable steps to protect the information you provide from theft, alternation or unauthorized inspection. 

**Your Rights:**

All personally identifiable information you provide to Harcourt is on a voluntary basis. If you do not wish to reveal such information, you are free to simply ignore these offerings. 

You may review and approve the information about you collected upon registration in Harcourt's customer database. Upon request, Harcourt will remove information from its customer database or change/correct personal information that you state is erroneous. However, you should understand that information about you in Harcourt's databases might come from a number of sources, including orders placed by you and third party mailing lists. 

**Privacy Contact:**

Please direct any questions regarding this policy to Harcourt at [hspwebmaster@harcourtschool.com](mailto:hspwebmaster@harcourtschool.com). 

**Links to Other Sites:**

The Learning Site may contain links to other Websites that are not under Harcourt's control. Such other sites do not necessarily follow this Privacy Policy. Harcourt is not responsible for the privacy policies of Web sites to which The Learning Site may link. 

**Modification of this Privacy Policy:**

Harcourt's practices may change periodically, so please check back here from time to time to review the current Privacy Policy. 

**Privacy Policies of Other Harcourt Companies:**

Due to the diverse nature of Harcourt's businesses, companies within the Harcourt family may have different privacy policies. In such cases, the privacy policy of the particular Harcourt company will be posted, and will supersede the terms of this document in the event of a conflict.
